<!DOCTYPE html PUBLIC "-//W3C//DTD XHTML 1.0 Transitional//EN" "http://www.w3.org/TR/xhtml1/DTD/xhtml1-transitional.dtd">
<html xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml">
    <head>
        <meta content="text/html; charset=us-ascii" http-equiv="content-type" />
        <title><!-- TITLE BEGIN -->Electric Flow integration with CICS CM<!-- TITLE END --></title>
        <link rel="stylesheet" href="../../plugins/@PLUGIN_KEY@/pluginhelp.css" type="text/css" media="screen" />
    </head>
    <!-- REST PLUGIN WIZARD HELP -->
    <body>
        <div class="help">
            <h1>@PLUGIN_KEY@</h1>
            <p>Plugin Version @PLUGIN_VERSION@</p>
            <hr style="margin-left: -10px; margin-top: 10px; height: 1px; width: 100%; color: #5981BD;" noshade="noshade" />
            <p>Revised on <!-- REVISION DATE BEGIN -->December 13, 2017<!-- REVISION DATE END --></p>
            <p>
                <!-- DESCRIPTION BEGIN -->This plugin integrates Commander with the CICS Configuration Manager (CM) tool for administering resource definitions in the CICS application server. It provides access to all CICS CM operations via the CICS CM SOAP API.
                <!-- DESCRIPTION END -->
            </p>
            <h2>Links</h2>
            <!-- LINKS BEGIN -->
            <a href="https://www.ibm.com/bs-en/marketplace/cics-configuration-management-tool" target="_blank">https://www.ibm.com/bs-en/marketplace/cics-configuration-management-tool</a>
            <!-- LINKS END -->
            <h1>Contents</h1>
            <ul>
                <!-- TOC BEGIN -->
                
                <h2>The EC-CICS-CM Procedures and What They Are Used For</h2>
                <p>For a CICS CM perspective, see <a href="https://www.ibm.com/support/knowledgecenter/en/SS2L7A_5.3.0/com.ibm.cics.cm.doc/ccv-api-summary.html">https://www.ibm.com/support/knowledgecenter/en/SS2L7A_5.3.0/com.ibm.cics.cm.doc/ccv-api-summary.html</a></p>
                <p>Here are the EC-CICS-CM procedures, grouped according to their purpose:</p>
                <ul>
		    <li>
		        <p>Manipulating objects and their data:</p>
		        <p><strong>Create*</strong> Create a resource definition (<a href="#CreateInOther">CreateInOther</a>) or a CICS Configuration Manager repository object (<a href="#CreateInRepository">CreateInRepository</a>).</p>
		        <p><strong>Update*</strong> Modify a resource definition (<a href="#UpdateInOther">UpdateInOther</a>) or a CICS Configuration Manager repository object (<a href="#UpdateInRepository">UpdateInRepository</a>).</p>
		        <p><strong><a href="#Copy">Copy</a></strong> Copy resource definitions between groups or CICS configurations.</p>
			<p><strong>Delete*</strong> Delete resource definitions (<a href="#DeleteFromOther">DeleteFromOther</a>) or CICS Configuration Manager repository objects (<a href="#DeleteFromRepository">DeleteFromRepository</a>).</p>
			<p><strong><a href="#Copy">Alter</a></strong> Alter selected attribute values across one or more resource definitions, without affecting other attribute values.</p>
			<p><strong>Rename*</strong> Rename resource definitions, and optionally move them to another group (<a href="#RenameResDef">RenameResDef</a>, or <a href="#RenameFromGroup">RenameFromGroup</a> to rename/move the contents of a resource group).<br /> </p>
	            </li>
		    <li>
		        <p>Associating objects with other objects:</p>
		        <p><strong>Add*</strong> Add objects to a container object, such as a change package (<a href="#AddResDefToChgPkg">AddResDefToChgPkg</a>, or <a href="#AddCmdToChgPkg">AddCmdToChgPkg</a> to add a command), to a resource group (<a href="#AddToResGrp">AddToResGrp</a>), or to a list (<a href="#AddToResDesc">AddToResDesc</a>).</p>
		        <p><strong>Remove*</strong> Remove objects from a container object, such as a change package (<a href="#RemoveResDefFromChgPkg">RemoveResDefFromChgPkg</a>, or <a href="#RemoveCmdToChgPkg">RemoveCmdToChgPkg</a> to remove a command), from a resource group (<a href="#RemoveFromResGrp">RemoveFromResGrp</a>), or list (<a href="#RemoveFromResDesc">RemoveFromResDesc</a>).<br /> </p>
		    </li>
		    <li>
		        <p>Retrieving object information:</p>
		        <p><strong>Inquire*</strong> Return all the fields for a single resource definition (<a href="#InquireInOther">InquireInOther</a>), CICS Configuration Manager repository object (<a href="#InquireInRepository">InquireInRepository</a>), or CICS Configuration Manager journal object (<a href="#InquireInJournal">InquireInJournal</a>).</p>
		        <p><strong>List*</strong> Return selected fields from one or more resource definitions (<a href="#ListFromOther">ListFromOther</a>, or <a href="#ListWithinResults">ListWithinResults</a> to filter the results), CICS Configuration Manager repository objects (<a href="#ListFromRepository">ListFromRepository</a>), or CICS Configuration Manager journal objects (<a href="#ListFromJournal">ListFromJournal</a>).<br /> </p>
		    </li>
		    <li>
		        <p>Packaging changes to resource definitions:</p>
		        <p><strong><a href="#Ready">Ready</a></strong> Indicate that the resource definitions in a change package are ready for migration.</p>
		        <p><strong><a href="#Unready">Unready</a></strong> Indicate that the resource definitions in a change package are no longer ready for migration.</p>
		        <p><strong><a href="#Approve">Approve</a></strong> Add to a change package the approval of a particular approver role.</p>
		        <p><strong><a href="#Disapprove">Disapprove</a></strong> Remove from a change package the approval of a particular approver role.</p>
		        <p><strong><a href="#Migrate">Migrate</a></strong> Copy the resource definitions in a change package from source to target CICS configurations, and invoke commands in the change package on target CICS configurations, according to the specified migration scheme.</p>
		        <p><strong><a href="#Backout">Backout</a></strong> Back out a previous change package migration.<br /> </p>
		    </li>
		    <li>
		        <p>Altering in-memory images of resource definitions in active CICS regions:</p>
		        <p><strong>Discard*</strong> Discard the in-memory image of resource definitions from active CICS regions (<a href="#DiscardChgPkg">DiscardChgPkg</a>, or <a href="#DiscardAdHoc">DiscardAdHoc</a> for arbitrary resource definitions not from a change package).</p>
		        <p><strong>Install*</strong> Dynamically make resource definitions available to an active CICS region (<a href="#InstallChgPkg">InstallChgPkg</a>, or <a href="#InstallAdHoc">InstallAdHoc</a> for arbitrary resource definitions not from a change package).</p>
		        <p><strong>Newcopy*</strong> Reload in-memory copies of resource definitions associated with a CICS program definition or document template definition (<a href="#NewcopyChgPkg">NewcopyChgPkg</a>, or <a href="#NewcopyAdHoc">NewcopyAdHoc</a> for arbitrary resource definitions not from a change package).<br /> </p>
		    </li>
		    <li>
		        <p>Importing resource definitions from an export file:</p>
		        <p><strong><a href="#Import">Import</a></strong> Import resource definitions from an export file received from another CICS Configuration Manager system. Optionally, if the export file contains change package details, also registers change packages in the importing CICS Configuration Manager repository.<br /> </p>
		    </li>
		    <li>
		        <p>Recovering historical versions of resource definitions from the journal:</p>
		        <p><strong><a href="#Recover">Recover</a></strong> Recovers before or after images of historical resource definitions from the journal.</p>
		    </li>
		</ul>
                <!-- TOC END -->
            </ul>
            <h2>Configuration</h2>
            <div id="CreateConfiguration">
                <a name="CreateConfiguration" id="CreateConfigurationLink"></a>
                <h2>Plugin Configurations</h2>
                <p>
                    Plugin configurations are sets of parameters that apply
                    across some or all of the plugin procedures. They
                    reduce repetition of common values, create
                    predefined parameter sets for end users, and
                    securely store credentials where needed. Each configuration
                    is given a unique name that is entered in designated
                    parameters on procedures that use them.<br /><br />
                </p>
                <h3>Creating Plugin Configurations</h3>
                <p>To create plugin configurations in ElectricFlow,
                do these steps:</p>
                <ol>
                    <li>Go to <b>Administration</b> &gt; <b>Plugins</b> to open the Plugin Manager.</li>
                    <li>Find the @PLUGIN_KEY@ row.</li>
                    <li>Click <b>Configure</b> to open the
                    @PLUGIN_KEY@ Configurations page.</li>
                    <li>Click <b>Create Configuration</b>.</li>
                    <li>To enable ElectricFlow server to communicate with the API,
                    enter the following information:<br /></li>
                    <!-- CONFIG PARAMS BEGIN -->
                    <table class="grid">
                        <thead>
                            <tr>
                                <th>Parameter</th>
                                <th>Description</th>
                            </tr>
                        </thead>
                        <tbody>
                            <tr>
                                <td class="required">Configuration</td>
                                <td>Unique name for the plugin configuration.</td>
                            </tr>

                            <tr>
                                <td>Description</td>
                                <td>Description for the plugin configuration.</td>
                            </tr>

                            <tr>
                                <td class="required">CICS CM SOAP URL</td>
                                <td>	
The URL of the SOAP interface of the CICS CM server to connect to (this should normally be of the format http://[server]:[port]/CICS/CWBA/CCVWSDSH/CCVADISP ).</td>
                            </tr>

                            <tr>
                                <td class="required">CICS CM Version</td>
                                <td>The CICS CM version number (normally the same as the CICS version number).</td>
                            </tr>

                            <tr>
                                <td class="required">Name of the connection</td>
                                <td>The name of the connection from the CSD to a specific CICS region.</td>
                            </tr>

                            <tr>
                                <td class="required">Credential</td>
                                <td>Credentials to connect.</td>
                            </tr>
                        </tbody>
                    </table><!-- CONFIG PARAMS END -->
                </ol>
                <p>The @PLUGIN_KEY@ Configurations page now shows the new configuration.</p>
                <h3>Editing Plugin Configurations</h3>
                <p>To edit plugin configurations in ElectricFlow,
                do these steps:</p>
                <ol>
                    <li>Go to <b>Administration</b> &gt; <b>Plugins</b> to open the Plugin Manager.</li>
                    <li>Find the @PLUGIN_KEY@ row.</li>
                    <li>Click <b>Configure</b> to open the Configurations page.</li>
                    <li>Find the configuration that you want to edit.</li>
                    <li>Click <b>Edit</b>.</li>
                    <li>Edit the parameters in the configuration.</li>
                    <li>Click <b>OK</b> to save the modified configuration.</li>
                </ol>
            </div>
            <h1>Procedures</h1>
            <!-- PROCEDURES BEGIN -->
            
            <!-- #### TODO KOSTYA Add all the other procedures. This is basically just copy-paste from
            the procedure's form and from the descriptions in the TOC above (for a procedure whose TOC
            description lists several procedures, cut it down to just the part relevant to this
            procedure). -->
            
            <div id="Backout">
                <a name="Backout" id="Backout" />
                <!-- Backout METADATA BEGIN -->
                <h3>Backout</h3>
                <p>Back out a previous change package migration.</p>
                <!-- Backout METADATA END -->
                <!-- Backout BEGIN -->
                <table class="grid">
                    <thead>
                        <tr>
                            <th>Parameter</th>
                            <th>Description</th>
                        </tr>
                    </thead>
                    <tbody>
                        <tr>
                            <td class="required">Configuration Name</td>
                            <td>The EC-CICS-CM configuration to use.</td>
                        </tr>
                        <tr>
                            <td class="required">Output Property:</td>
                            <td>The property that results will be returned into.</td>
                        </tr>
                        <tr>
                            <td class="required">Change Package ID</td>
                            <td>The change package ID of the change to back out.</td>
                        </tr>
                        <tr>
                            <td class="required">Scheme</td>
                            <td>The migration scheme of the change to back out.</td>
                        </tr>
                        <tr>
                            <td>Event ID</td>
                            <td>The eventID of the execution of the Migrate command for the specified change package and migration scheme to back out (if omitted, it defaults to the most recent Migrate command for that change package and migration scheme).</td>
                        </tr>
                    </tbody>
                </table>
                <!-- Backout END -->
            </div>

            <!-- PROCEDURES END -->
        </div>
        <!-- RELEASE NOTES BEGIN -->
        <!-- RELEASE NOTES END -->
    </body>
</html>
